(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
今だからこそ、逆に昭和。
Precisely because it's now, we're doing Showa.
宝鐘マリン3周年記念企画、
Marine Houshou 3rd Anniversary Project:
宝鐘マリン完全プロデュース、
Fully produced by Marine Houshou,
ホロライブ昭和歌謡祭。
the Hololive Showa Song Festival.
バーチャル関東のホロライブスタジオよりお届けいたします。
Brought to you from the Hololive Studio in Virtual Kanto.
司会は昭和歌謡に疎い大空スバルから、
Our hosts range from Subaru Ozora, who is unfamiliar with Showa pop,
土曜日に歌謡曲を歌うアキ・ローゼンタールまで、
to Aki Rosenthal, who sings pop songs on Saturdays.
大勢の豪華ホロライブメンバーが昭和歌謡曲に挑戦。
Many gorgeous Hololive members will take on Showa pop songs.
存分に昭和ワールドをお楽しみください。
Please enjoy the world of Showa to your heart's content.
読み捨てられる 雑誌のように 私のページが めくられるたびに
Like a magazine that's read and thrown away, every time my page is turned,
放り出されて しまうのかしら それが知りたくて とても
I wonder if I'll be cast aside? I really want to know...
あなたの瞳の 奥に旅してく わたしの
I'm traveling deep into your eyes... my...
センチメンタル・ジャーニー
Sentimental Journey.
つぼみのままで 夢を見ていたい 影絵のように 美しい
I want to keep dreaming while still a bud, as beautiful as a shadow play...
物語だけ見ていたいわ
I want to see only the stories.
マリンはまだ 17だから
Because Marine is still only seventeen.
何かにさそわれて あなたにさらわれて
Tempted by something, carried away by you...
センチメンタル・ジャーニー
Sentimental Journey.
見知らぬ国の 謎の湖 のぞき見たくなる 不思議な気持ち
A mysterious lake in a foreign land, a strange feeling makes me want to peek.
自分でもさえも 怖いほどなの 咲かせた恋なら ずっと
It's scary even to myself. If it's a love that bloomed, then forever...
大事にしていて 貰えるのかしら 判らない
I wonder if you'll treasure me? I don't know.
センチメンタル・ジャーニー
Sentimental Journey.
扉の前で ためらいながらも 背中をそっと 押されたい
Though I hesitate before the door, I want to be gently pushed from behind.
見ないふりして 許してね
Please forgive me while pretending not to see.
マリンはまだ 17だから
Marine is still 17 so...
何かにさそわれて あなたにさらわれて
Invited by something, snatched away by you
センチメンタル・ジャーニー
Sentimental Journey
1曲目はセンチメンタル・ジャーニーをお聞きいただきました。
We just heard the first song, Sentimental Journey.
はい。「伊代はまだ16だから」を「マリンはまだ17だから」と替え歌にしていたようですね。
Yes. It seems she changed "Iyo is still 16" to "Marine is still 17".
いつまで17歳気分なんでしょうかね。
I wonder how long she'll feel like she's 17.
宝鐘マリンは永遠に17歳です。
Houshou Marine is eternally 17.
はい、お肌もまだピチピチです。
Yes, her skin is still supple.
いや、でも、マリンさんまだまだ17歳としてはイケてるほうなんじゃないでしょうか。
But really, Marine-san is doing pretty well for a 17-year-old, isn't she?
そうなんですかね？でもちょっとあの、股関節が痛いみたいな聞いたことがありますが。
Is that so? But I've heard something about her hip joints hurting.
そうなんですか？そんな情報が... あったような気がします。
Oh, really? I feel like... there was such information.
じゃあ股関節も大事にしていただいて、全身ピチピチの17歳でいてほしいですね。
Then I hope she takes care of her hip joints and stays a supple 17-year-old all over.
そうですね。
That's true.
はい。それでは次の曲参りましょう。
Yes. Now, let's move on to the next song.
どうぞ！
Here it is!
赤いスイートピー
Red Sweet Pea
作詞：松本隆
作曲：呉田軽穂
Lyrics: Matsumoto Takashi
Composition: Kureta Karuho
この曲を選んだのは、コラボ相手が「赤井」はあとだからという理由だそうです。
The reason she chose this song is apparently because her collab partner is "Akai" Haato.
なるほど。少し安直ですが、楽しみです。
I see. A bit simplistic, but I'm looking forward to it.
そうですね。では、お二人の素敵な歌声を聞いていただきましょう。
Indeed. Well then, let's listen to their wonderful singing voices.
それでは、歌っていただきましょう。赤いスイートピーです。
Now, please perform: Akai Sweet Pea.
春色の汽車に乗って 海に連れて行ってよ
Take me to the sea on a spring-colored train
煙草の匂いのシャツに そっと寄りそうから
I'll gently lean against your shirt that smells of tobacco
何故 知りあった日から 半年過ぎても
Why, even though half a year has passed since the day we met...
あなたって手も握らない
You don't even hold my hand
I will follow you あなたについてゆきたい
I will follow you, I want to follow you
I will follow you ちょっぴり気が弱いけど
I will follow you, even though you're a bit timid
素敵な人だから
Because you're a wonderful person
心の岸辺に咲いた 赤いスイートピー
The red sweet pea blooming on the shores of my heart
四月の雨に降られて 駅のベンチで二人
Caught in the April rain, the two of us on a station bench
他に人影もなくて 不意に気まずくなる
No one else in sight, it suddenly gets awkward
何故 あなたが時計を チラッとみるたび
Why, every time you glance at your watch...
泣きそうな気分になるの？
Do I feel like I'm about to cry?
I will follow you 翼の生えたブーツで
I will follow you, with boots that have grown wings
I will follow you あなたと同じ青春
I will follow you, through the same youth as yours
走ってゆきたいの
I want to go running
線路の脇のつぼみは 赤いスイートピー
The buds by the tracks are red sweet peas
好きよ 今日まで逢った誰より
I love you, more than anyone I've met until today
I will follow you あなたの生き方が好き
I will follow you, I love the way you live
このまま帰れない 帰れない
I can't go home like this, I can't go home
心に春が来た日は 赤いスイートピー
On the day spring came to my heart, the red sweet pea
赤いスイートピー
Red Sweet Pea
2曲目は宝鐘マリンと赤井はあとで「赤いスイートピー」をお聴きいただきました。
For our second song, Houshou Marine and Akai Haato performed "Red Sweet Pea."
いやぁ、二人ともすごく清楚でしたね。
Man, those two were so ladylike and pure.
そうですね。赤井さんでしたね。
They were. That was certainly Akai-san.
いや、赤井さんでした。
Yes, it was Akai-san.
そうですね。はあちゃまではなかったですね。
Right. It definitely wasn't Haachama.
誰ですかその方は？
And who might that be?
存じ上げませんか？
You don't know her?
あ、そうですか。
Oh, is that so?
まあ、昭和の世界なのでね。
Well, we are in the Showa era world.
なるほど。
I see.
はあちゃまは令和に生きております。
Haachama lives in the Reiwa era.
なるほど。
That makes sense.
「赤いスイートピー」はでも、あの、アイドルソングらしくてとても良かったですね。
"Red Sweet Pea" was great, it felt like a classic idol song.
そうですね。宝鐘マリンは「赤いスイートピー」のこと最初チューリップだと思ってたそうです。
Indeed. Apparently, Houshou Marine thought "Red Sweet Pea" meant a tulip at first.
あ、そうなんですか。全然違いますけど。
Oh, really? They're completely different.
そうなんですよね。
They sure are.
それでは次の曲に参りましょう。
Well then, let's move on to the next song.
どうぞ！
Here it is!
年下の男の子
Younger Boy
真赤なリンゴを頬ばる ネイビーブルーのTシャツ
Biting into a bright red apple, wearing a navy blue T-shirt
あいつは あいつはかわいい
He is, he is so cute
年下の男の子
My younger boy
淋しがりやで 生意気で
Always lonely, and so cheeky
にくらっしいけど好きなの
He's annoying, but I love him
L・O・V・E 投げキッス
L-O-V-E, a blown kiss
私のこと好きかしら
I wonder if he likes me
はっきりきかせて
Tell me clearly
ボタンのとれてるポケット 汚れて丸めたハンカチ
A pocket with a missing button, a dirty, crumpled handkerchief
あいつは あいつはかわいい
He is, he is so cute
年下の男の子
My younger boy
デートの時間に遅れる いつでもけんかをしかける
Late for our date, always trying to pick a fight
あいつは あいつはかわいい
He is, he is so cute
年下の男の子
My younger boy
忘れん坊で わがままで
Forgetful, and so selfish
いじわるだけど好きなの
He's mean, but I love him
L・O・V・E 投げキッス
L-O-V-E, a blown kiss
私のこと好きかしら
I wonder if he likes me
はっきりきかせて
Tell me clearly
片方なくした手袋 ほどけたまんまの靴ひも
A missing glove, shoelaces left untied
あいつは あいつはかわいい
He is, he is so cute
年下の男の子
My younger boy
あいつは あいつはかわいい
He is, he is so cute
年下の男の子
My younger boy
あいつは あいつはかわいい
He is, he is so cute
年下の男の子
My younger boy
宝鐘マリン、アキ・ローゼンタール、癒月ちょこで「年下の男の子」でした。
That was Houshou Marine, Aki Rosenthal, and Yuzuki Choco with "Younger Boy."
はい。すごくお姉さんの三人でセクシーでしたね。
Yes. Those three big sisters were very sexy.
そうですね。こちら、アキ・ローゼはやっぱりリンゴが歌詞に出てきますので。
True. For AkiRose, the lyrics about the apple were a perfect fit.
なるほど。真っ赤なリンゴのシナジーがありまして。
I see. There was some "bright red apple" synergy there.
やはり「年下の男の子」といえば、この女ということで、癒月ちょこさん。
And when you think of "Younger Boy," you think of this woman, Yuzuki Choco-san.
ちょっとこう... たぶらかしそうな感じが...
It has a bit of a... seductive feel to it...
そうですね、なるほど。
Right, I see.
この中に白銀ノエルさんもいたら、よりもうすごいなとは思うんですけども...
If Shirogane Noel was here too, I think it would be even more incredible...
この後まだ、出演が結構多数残ってるということで。
But there are still quite a few guest appearances left after this.
多数？
Many?
そうなんです。
That's right.
あ、そうなんですねー。
Oh, I see!
その4人での歌唱もちょっと見てみたいですね。
I'd love to see a performance with those four as well.
そうですね。
Definitely.
ぜひ、あの、動画など楽しみに、しております。
I'm really looking forward to the videos and such.
はい。それではお次参りましょう。
Yes. Now, let's move on to the next one.
どうぞ！
Here you go!
私たち二人がオバさんになっても
Even if the two of us become old ladies...
私がオバさんになっても
作詞：森高千里　作曲：斉藤英夫
Watashi ga Oba-san ni Natte mo
Lyrics: Chisato Moritaka | Composition: Hideo Saito
愛してほしいでござる！
...we want you to love us-degozaru!
風真いろはさんは、クッキーを焼いて皆さんに配っていましたね。
Kazama Iroha was baking cookies and giving them to everyone.
美味しそうでしたね。はい。
They looked delicious. Yes.
それでは歌っていただきましょう。
Now, let's hear them sing.
私がオバさんになっても。
Watashi ga Oba-san ni Natte mo.
秋が終われば冬が来る ほんとに早いわ
When autumn ends, winter comes. It's really fast.
夏休みには二人して サイパンへ行ったわ
During summer vacation, the two of us went to Saipan.
日焼けした肌まだ黒い 楽しい思い出
My tanned skin is still dark, a happy memory.
来年も又サイパンへ 泳ぎに行きたいわ
Next year, I want to go to Saipan again to swim.
あなたは優しい人ね 私を抱きよせて
You're a kind person, aren't you? Drawing me close...
ずっとこのままいようと KISSをした
Kissing, saying "Let's stay like this forever."
私がオバさんになっても 泳ぎに連れてくの？
Even when I become an old lady, will you take me swimming?
派手な水着はとてもムリよ 若い子には負けるわ
Flashy swimsuits are impossible, I'll lose to the young girls.
私がオバさんになっても 本当に変わらない？
Even when I become an old lady, will you really not change?
とても心配だわ あなたが 若い子が好きだから
I'm so worried because you like young girls.
そんな話はバカげてる あなたは言うけれど
You say that kind of talk is ridiculous, but...
女ざかりは19だと あなたが言ったのよ
You're the one who said a woman's prime is 19.
だけど何くわぬ顔で 私を見つめて
But you look at me with an innocent face...
あれは冗談だったと KISSをした
Kissing, saying "That was just a joke."
私がオバさんになっても ディスコに連れてくの？
Even when I become an old lady, will you take me to the disco?
ミニスカートはとてもムリよ 若い子には負けるわ
Miniskirts are impossible, I'll lose to the young girls.
私がオバさんになっても ドライブしてくれる？
Even when I become an old lady, will you take me for a drive?
オープンカーの屋根はずして かっこよく走ってよ
Take the roof off the convertible and drive coolly.
私がオバさんになったら あなたはおじさんよ
When I become an old lady, you'll be an old man.
かっこいいことばかり言っても お腹が出てくるのよ
Even if you say cool things, your stomach will start sticking out.
私がオバさんになっても 本当に変わらない？
Even when I become an old lady, will you really not change?
とても心配だわ あなたが 若い子が好きだから
I'm so worried because you like young girls.
宝鐘マリン、風真いろはで「私がオバさんになっても」でした。
That was Houshou Marine and Kazama Iroha with 'Watashi ga Oba-san ni Natte mo'.
はい。すごくフレッシュで可愛らしかったですねー。
Yes. That was very fresh and cute, wasn't it?
はい。風真いろはさんの元気な姿がとてもよくて、とってもフレッシュでよかったと思います。
Yes. Kazama Iroha's energy was great, and I think it was wonderfully fresh.
うん。二人ともとてもフレッシュでしたね。
Mhm. Both of them were so fresh.
そうですね。
Indeed.
はい、とても良かったと思います。はい。
Yes, I think it was very good. Yes.
ちなみに、ミオさんはおばあちゃんになったらどんなおばあちゃんになりたいですか？
By the way, Mio-san, what kind of grandmother do you want to be when you grow up?
えっと、ポケットにアメちゃんが入ってるみたいなおばあちゃんになりたいです。
Um, I want to be the kind of grandmother who has candy in her pocket.
なるほど、はい。いいですね。優しいおばあちゃんですね。はい。
I see, yes. That's nice. A kind grandmother. Yes.
フブキさんは？
What about you, Fubuki-san?
80になってもゲームセンターに通うおばあちゃんになっていたいたいす。
I want to be a grandmother who goes to the game center even when I'm 80.
ゲーセンおばあちゃんってことですね。はい。
A game center grandma, then. Yes.
それでは次の曲まいりましょう。
Well then, let's move on to the next song.
どうぞ！
Please!
夢の中へ
Into the Dream
宝鐘マリンは一体どんな夢を見ているのか。そんなマリンの夢の中へ飛び込みたい。
What kind of dream is Houshou Marine seeing? I want to dive into such a dream of Marine's.
今からダイブですか？
Are you diving now?
それでは聴いてください。夢の中へ。
Well then, please listen. Into the Dream.
探しものは何ですか？ 見つけにくいものですか？
What is it you're looking for? Is it something hard to find?
カバンの中も つくえの中も 探したけれど見つからないのに
I looked in my bag and in my desk, but I still can't find it.
まだまだ探す気ですか？ それより僕と踊りませんか？
Do you still intend to keep looking? Wouldn't you rather dance with me instead?
夢の中へ 夢の中へ 行ってみたいと思いませんか？
Into the dream, into the dream, don't you want to try going there?
休む事も許されず 笑う事は止められて
Not allowed to rest, forbidden from laughing.
はいつくばって はいつくばって 一体何を探しているのか
Crawling, crawling, just what are you looking for?
探すのをやめた時 見つかる事もよくある話で
It's often the case that you find it when you stop looking.
踊りましょう 夢の中へ 行ってみたいと思いませんか？
Let's dance, into the dream, don't you want to try going there?
探しものは何ですか？ まだまだ探す気ですか？
What is it you're looking for? Do you still intend to keep looking?
夢の中へ 夢の中へ 行ってみたいと思いませんか？
Into the dream, into the dream, don't you want to try going there?
宝鐘マリン、獅白ぼたんで『夢の中へ』でした。
That was 'Into the Dream' by Houshou Marine and Shishiro Botan.
二人のハーモニーがとても気持ち良かったですね。
The harmony between those two was very pleasant, wasn't it?
いや、すごくお耳が気持ち良くなりましたね。はい。
Yes, it felt really good on the ears. Yes.
こちらの選曲なんですけども、『彼氏彼女の事情』というアニメの主題歌。
Regarding this song selection, it's the theme song for the anime 'His and Her Circumstances'.
はい。で、たまたま聴いたところが昭和の曲だったということで選曲したそうです。
Yes. And they chose it because they happened to hear it and it was a Showa era song.
そうですね、リメイクの曲ですね。はい、いい曲でした。
That's right, it's a remake. Yes, it was a good song.
今回獅白ぼたんさんは、歌のコラボをしたことがないということでお誘いしてみたみたいです。
It seems they invited Shishiro Botan-san because she said she had never done a singing collab before.
ちなみに最近見た宝鐘マリンの夢なんですけども、家の中に生えたキノコを食べたところ腹痛を起こしたという...
By the way, regarding a dream Houshou Marine had recently, she ate a mushroom that grew in her house and got a stomachache...
あ、大変ですね。
Oh, that's terrible.
ちょっと悲しい夢を見ていたそうです。それでは次の曲まいりましょう。
Apparently, she was having a slightly sad dream. Well then, let's move on to the next song.
どうぞ！
Please!
DESIRE -情熱-
DESIRE -Jonetsu-
魔界様に堕ちていきたい隊員のもとへ。どちらの胸元に飛び込むのか迷いますね。
To the fans who want to fall for the Demon World Lord. It's hard to decide which one's arms to dive into.
それでは聴いていただきましょう。『DESIRE -情熱-』。
Well then, please listen to 'DESIRE -Jonetsu-'.
Get up, Get up, Get up, Get up, Burning Love
やりきれない程 退屈な時があるわ
There are times when it's so boring I can't stand it.
あなたといても
Even when I'm with you.
喋るぐらいなら 踊っていたいの今は
If it's just talking, I'd rather be dancing right now.
硝子のディスコティック
A glass discotheque.
そう みんな堕天使ね
That's right, everyone's a fallen angel.
汗が羽のかわりに飛んでる
Sweat is flying instead of feathers.
何にこだわればいいの
What should I be fixated on?
愛の見えない時代の恋人達ね
Lovers in an era where love is invisible.
まっさかさまに墜ちて desire
Falling headlong, desire.
炎のように燃えて desire
Burning like a flame, desire.
恋も dance, dance, dance, dance ほど
Love also, just like a dance, dance, dance, dance,
夢中になれない なんてね 淋しい
I can't get into it. How lonely.
Get up, Get up, Get up, Get up, Burning heart
腕を離してよ
Let go of my arm.
キスをされるのもごめん
I'm sorry, I don't want to be kissed.
気分じゃないの
I'm not in the mood.
ヒールを脱ぎ捨て感じているのよ
Throwing off my heels, I'm feeling it,
夜の孤独な長さを
the length of the night's loneliness.
そう 多分 贅沢な悩み
Yes, it's probably a selfish worry.
分かっているわ これでも
I know that, even so.
何を信じればいいの
What should I believe in?
スキャンダルさえ
Even a scandal
時代のエクスタシィよ
is the ecstasy of the era.
ぶつかり合って 縺れ desire
Colliding and tangling, desire.
星のかけらを 掴め desire
Grasp the fragments of stars, desire.
夢はそうよ 見る前に
Dreams, that's right, if they fade
醒めてしまったら
before you even see them,
何にもならない
they come to nothing.
Get up, Get up, Get up, Get up
Burning love
まっさかさまに墜ちて desire
Falling headlong, desire.
炎のように燃えて desire
Burning like a flame, desire.
恋も dance, dance, dance, dance ほど
Love also, just like a dance, dance, dance, dance,
夢中になれない なんてね
I can't get into it.
淋しい
How lonely.
Get up, Get up, Get up, Get up
Burning heart
Burning love
宝鐘マリン、常闇トワで『DESIRE -情熱-』でした！
That was Houshou Marine and Tokoyami Towa with 'DESIRE -Jounetsu-'!
はい、すごくパワフルな雰囲気で素晴らしかったですね！
Yes, it had a very powerful atmosphere and was wonderful!
そうですね、迫力がありましたね！
It certainly did, it was very impactful!
今回ですね、このトワさんのこの中森明菜さんへのシナジーがすごくて...
This time, the synergy Towa-san had with Akina Nakamori's style was amazing...
マリンさんはこの歌お箱だったらしいんですけど、少し食われてしまったというお話でした
Apparently, this is one of Marine-san's signature songs, but she said she felt a bit overshadowed.
パワー負けしてしまいましたね。食われてしまったと言えば、そういえば一つ情報があるんですけども...
She was outpowered. Speaking of being overshadowed, I actually have a piece of info here...
最近宝鐘マリンさんがハマっている食べ物があるそうで...
Apparently, there's a food Houshou Marine-san has been into lately...
マイブーム、しらすだそうです
Her current obsession is whitebait.
※ハマっていません
*She's not actually into it.
生しらすの方ですかね？
Does she mean raw whitebait?
あ、ちょっとそこまでは聞いてなかったんですけど...
Ah, I didn't quite hear that much detail...
終わった時聞こうと思います
I'll try asking her when it's over.
というわけで、次の曲参りましょう。どうぞ！
With that, let's move on to the next song. Here it is!
初恋の味はレモンのように酸っぱいそうです。
They say the taste of first love is sour like a lemon.
ですがキスの味も酸っぱいそうで。それでは聴いていただきましょう。初恋。
But they say the taste of a kiss is also sour. Now, please listen to 'Hatsukoi'.
五月雨は緑色
The early summer rain is green-colored.
悲しくさせたよ 一人の午後は
It made me feel sad, this afternoon alone.
恋をして淋しくて
Being in love and feeling lonely,
届かぬ想いを 暖めていた
I was nursing my unreachable feelings.
好きだよと言えずに 初恋は
Without being able to say "I love you," first love is...
ふりこ細工の心
A heart like a pendulum mechanism
放課後の校庭を 走る君がいた
There you were, running across the schoolyard after school
遠くで僕は いつでも君を探してた
From afar, I was always looking for you
浅い夢だから 胸をはなれない
Because it's a shallow dream, it won't leave my heart
夕映えはあんず色
The evening glow is the color of apricots
帰り道一人 口笛吹いて
Walking home alone, whistling a tune
名前さえ呼べなくて
Unable to even call out your name
とらわれた心 見つめていたよ
My captivated heart was gazing at you
好きだよと言えずに 初恋は
Without being able to say "I love you," first love is...
ふりこ細工の心
A heart like a pendulum mechanism
風に舞った花びらが 水面を乱すように
Like petals dancing in the wind, disturbing the water's surface
愛という字書いてみては ふるえてたあの頃
Trying to write the word "love," I was trembling back then
浅い夢だから 胸をはなれない
Because it's a shallow dream, it won't leave my heart
放課後の校庭を 走る君がいた
There you were, running across the schoolyard after school
遠くで僕は いつでも君を探してた
From afar, I was always looking for you
浅い夢だから 胸をはなれない
Because it's a shallow dream, it won't leave my heart
胸をはなれない
It won't leave my heart
宝鐘マリン、大空スバルで「初恋」でした。
That was Houshou Marine and Oozora Subaru with "Hatsukoi."
いや、とても甘酸っぱい雰囲気でしたね。
Man, that was a very bittersweet atmosphere.
そうですね。こちら企画のまーちゃんとすーくんから来てるそうですね。
Right. It seems this comes from the Maa-chan and Suu-kun project.
なるほど。はい。あの企画の中で幼馴染の設定をそのまま曲のコラボで使ったということですね。
I see. So they used the childhood friend setting from that project for this song collab.
そうですね。はい。
Exactly.
ちなみに、何かこう甘酸っぱい記憶ってありますか？
By the way, do you have any bittersweet memories?
甘酸っぱい記憶ですか？はい。あの、学校帰りに生えている野いちごを食べた時が一番酸っぱかったですね。
Bittersweet memories? Well, the time I ate wild strawberries on the way home from school was the sourest.
甘酸っぱいですねー。
That's quite bittersweet.
※これは実話です
*This is a true story
それでは次の曲まいりましょう。
Now, let's move on to the next song.
どうぞ。
Here it is.
やかましい娘がさらにやかましくなりました。それでは聴いていただきましょう、学園天国。
The noisy girls have gotten even noisier. Please listen to: Gakuen Tengoku.
Are you ready? Yeah!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
あいつもこいつもあの席を ただ一つねらっているんだよ
Every one of them is aiming for that one seat
このクラスで一番の美人の隣を
The seat right next to the prettiest girl in class
あー みんなライバルさ
Ah, everyone's a rival
あー いのちがけだよ
Ah, it's a life-or-death struggle
運命の女神さまよ このぼくにほほえんで 一度だけでも
Oh, Goddess of Fate, smile upon me, just this once
勉強する気もしない気も この時にかかっているんだよ
Whether I feel like studying or not depends on this moment
もし駄目ならこのぼくは もうグレちまうよ
If it doesn't work out, I'm just gonna become a delinquent
学園天国
Gakuen Tengoku (School Heaven)
ヘーイ・ヘイ・ヘイ・ヘイ・ヘーイ！
Hey hey hey hey hey!
ヘーイ・ヘイ・ヘイ・ヘイ・ヘイ・ヘイ・ヘーイ！
Hey hey hey hey hey hey hey!
ヘイ！ ヘイ！ ヘイ！ ヘイ！ ヘイ！ ヘイ！ ヘイ！ ウォー！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Wow!
二枚目気どりの秀才や
The smart guy acting all cool,
あのいやな悪番長も
and even that nasty delinquent boss,
胸はずませ待っている
are all waiting with hearts racing
どの席になるか
to see which seat they'll get.
あー あの横顔を
Ah, that side profile...
あー 見つめられたら
Ah, if our eyes were to meet,
Yeah yeah yeah!
授業中 天国だよ
it would be heaven during class!
It's heaven during class!
このぼくにしあわせを
Give me happiness
与えておくれ
and grant it to me!
Hey!
勉強する気もしない気も
Whether I feel like studying or not,
この時にかかっているんだよ
everything depends on this moment.
もし駄目ならこのぼくは
If I fail, I might just
もうグレちまうよ
go off the rails!
Hey!
宝鐘マリン、犬神ころね、
Houshou Marine, Inugami Korone,
白銀ノエル、雪花ラミィ、
Shirogane Noel, Yukihana Lamy,
やかまし娘で『学園天国』でした。
that was 'Gakuen Tengoku' by the Noisy Girls.
元気いっぱい歌っていただきましたね。
They sang with so much energy!
そうですね。やかましいのか、かしましいのか
True. I don't know if they're 'noisy' or 'chattering',
わからないですけども、ちょっと意味が重複してますね。失礼いたしました。
but the meaning is a bit redundant. My apologies.
はい。というわけで、ラミィさんのですね、歌唱がすごく、あの高い声が出ていて
Right. Anyway, Lamy-san's singing was great, those high notes...
高温出てましたね。
She was hitting those high notes.
すごく、あの、よかったです。
It was really, really good.
かっこよかったです。
It was cool.
はい。そしてころねさんのタップダンス。
Yes. And Korone-san's tap dance.
いや、あれすごいですね。
Man, that was incredible.
足が5、6本に見えました。
Her legs looked like there were five or six of them!
すごくいっぱい見えましたね。
They really looked like they were moving fast, didn't they?
はい。そしてここでノエルさんが登場と。
Yes. And here, Noel-san makes her entrance.
ついにやってきましたね。
She's finally here.
はい。このあともまだ白銀ノエルさんは出番を控えてるとか。
Right. Shirogane Noel-san will be appearing again later...
楽しみですね。
I'm looking forward to it!
それではこのあと、夏の海をテーマにした曲を3曲連続でお送りいたします。
Now then, we will be performing three songs in a row with a summer sea theme.
もう秋なんですけどもね。
Even though it's already autumn.
残暑ですかね。
Lingering summer heat, perhaps?
まだ暑い日が続いております。
The hot days are still continuing.
それでは聴いていただきましょう、3曲連続でどうぞ。
Well then, please listen to these three songs in a row. Here they are.
どうぞ。
Please enjoy.
夏のお嬢さん
Natsu no Ojou-san (Summer Lady)
作詞 笠間ジュン 作曲 佐々木勉
Lyrics: Jun Kasama, Composition: Tsutomu Sasaki
チュウ・チュウ・チュウ・チュウ・チュウ
Chu chu chu chu chu
夏のお嬢さん ビキニがとっても似合うよ
Summer lady, that bikini suits you so well!
しげきてきさ クラクラしちゃう
It's so stimulating, it makes me dizzy!
チュウ・チュウ・チュウ・チュウ・チュウ
Chu chu chu chu chu
潮風をすりぬけ スケートボードに乗って
Slipping through the sea breeze on a skateboard,
むかえに行く 待っておくれ
I'm coming to get you, so please wait for me!
君は僕の あこがれのひとなんだよ
You are the one I've been longing for!
アイスクリーム ユースクリーム 恋する季節
Ice cream, you scream, the season of love!
ビーチ・パラソル ひくくして かくれる
I'll lower the beach parasol and hide,
アイスクリーム ユースクリーム 好きさ
Ice cream, you scream, I love you!
お嬢さん お嬢さん
Lady, oh lady!
ラ・ラ・ラ・ラ・ラ・ラ...
La la la la la la...
チュウ・チュウ・チュウ・チュウ・チュウ
Chu chu chu chu chu
夏のお嬢さん 浜辺の人気さらって
Summer lady, sweeping up all the popularity on the beach,
とんでいるね ヤキモキしちゃう
you're flying high, it makes me so anxious!
チュウ・チュウ・チュウ・チュウ・チュウ
Chu chu chu chu chu
波のりをするなら 君の似顔絵かいた
If you're going surfing, I've painted your portrait
サーフボード かしてあげるよ
on the surfboard I'll lend you!
僕は君に 首ったけなんだよ
I'm head over heels for you!
アイスクリーム ユースクリーム 恋する季節
Ice cream, you scream, the season of love!
砂に書いたよ テレながら ラブレター
I shyly wrote a love letter in the sand,
アイスクリーム ユースクリーム 好きさ
Ice cream, you scream, I love you!
お嬢さん お嬢さん
Lady, oh lady!
僕ら君に 首ったけなんだよ
We're head over heels for you!
アイスクリーム ユースクリーム 恋する季節
Ice cream, you scream, the season of love!
砂に書いたよ テレながら ラブレター
I shyly wrote a love letter in the sand,
アイスクリーム ユースクリーム 好きさ
Ice cream, you scream, I love it
お嬢さん お嬢さん
Young lady, young lady
渚のシンドバッド
Nagisa no Sindbad
アアア　アアア…
Aa, aa...
渚のシンドバッド
Nagisa no Sindbad
ここかと思えば またまたあちら
Just when I thought you're here, you're over there
浮気なひとね
What a fickle person you are
サーフィンボード 小わきにかかえ
Holding a surfboard under your arm
美女から美女へ
Going from one beauty to another
ビキニがとっても お似合いですと
Telling me my bikini looks great on me
肩など抱いて
While putting your arm around my shoulder
ちょいとお兄さん なれなれしいわ
Hey there, mister, you're being quite familiar
くちびる盗む 早わざは
That quick move of stealing a kiss
うわさ通りだわ
Is just like the rumors
あなたシンドバッド
You're a Sindbad
セクシー あなたはセクシー
Sexy, you are sexy
私は いちころで ダウンよ
I'm down for the count in an instant
もう あなたにあなたに おぼれる
Now I'm drowning in you, in you
波乗りあざやか 拍手をあびて
Surfing skillfully, showered with applause
キッスの嵐
A storm of kisses
あちらのパラソル こちらのパラソル
A parasol over there and a parasol over here
ウインク投げて
Winking at them
夜ふけになったら あなたの部屋へ
When it's late at night, into your room
しのんで行くよ
I'll sneak in
ちょいとお兄さん いい気なものね
Hey there, mister, aren't you full of yourself
うっとりさせる テクニック
Your technique for making me swoon
腹が立つほどよ
Is enough to make me angry
あなたシンドバッド
You're a Sindbad
セクシー あなたはセクシー
Sexy, you are sexy
私は いちころで ダウンよ
I'm down for the count in an instant
もう あなたにあなたに おぼれる
Now I'm drowning in you, in you
青い水平線を いま駆け抜けてく
I'm running through the blue horizon now
とぎすまされた
Sharpened
時の流れ感じて
Feeling the flow of time
AH ときめきへと
Ah, towards excitement
動き出す世界は
The world begins to move
忘れかけてた
I had almost forgotten
遠い夢の訪れ
The arrival of a distant dream
RIDE ON TIME
さまよう想いなら
If your thoughts are wandering
やさしく受け止めて
Accept them gently
そっと包んで
And wrap them softly
RIDE ON TIME
心に火を点けて
Light a fire in your heart
あふれる喜びに
In overflowing joy
拡がれ RIDE ON TIME
Spread out, ride on time
僕の輝く未来
My shining future
さあ回り始めて
Come, start turning
虚ろな日々も
Even empty days
全て愛に溶け込む
Everything melts into love
AH 何という朝
Ah, what a morning
今すぐ君のもと
I'll go to you right now
届けに行こう
Let's go deliver it
燃える心迷わず
This burning heart without hesitation
RIDE ON TIME 時よ走り出せ
Ride on time, time, start running
RIDE ON TIME, oh time, start running
愛よ光り出せ 目もくらむほど
Love, start shining, enough to dazzle me
RIDE ON TIME 心に火を点けて
RIDE ON TIME, light a fire in my heart
飛び立つ魂に送るよ
I'll send it to the soul taking flight
RIDE ON TIME
届けに行こう
Let's go deliver it
燃える心
This burning heart
今こそ
Right now
RIDE ON TIME 時よ走り出せ
RIDE ON TIME, oh time, start running
愛よ光り出せ
Love, start shining
目もくらむほど
Enough to dazzle me
RIDE ON TIME 心に火を点けて
RIDE ON TIME, light a fire in my heart
飛び立つ魂に送るよ
I'll send it to the soul taking flight
RIDE ON TIME
RIDE ON TIME さまよう想いなら
RIDE ON TIME, if they're wandering thoughts
やさしく受け止めて
Accept them gently
そっと包んで
And wrap them softly
RIDE ON TIME 心に火を点けて
RIDE ON TIME, light a fire in my heart
あふれる喜びに拡がれ
Spread into overflowing joy
RIDE ON TIME
RIDE ON TIME 時よ走り出せ
RIDE ON TIME, oh time, start running
愛よ光り出せ
Love, start shining
目もくらむほど
Enough to dazzle me
RIDE ON TIME 心に火を点けて
RIDE ON TIME, light a fire in my heart
飛び立つ魂に送るよ
I'll send it to the soul taking flight
RIDE ON TIME
宝鐘マリン、湊あくあで「夏色のお嬢さん」。
Houshou Marine and Minato Aqua with "Natsuiro no Ojou-san."
一伊那尓栖で「渚のシンドバッド」。
Ninomae Ina'nis with "Nagisa no Sinbad."
がうる・ぐらで「RIDE ON TIME」でした。
That was Gawr Gura with "RIDE ON TIME."
とっても可愛らしい3曲で、夏らしかったですね。
Three very cute songs, they felt like summer, didn't they?
そうですね。まだまだ夏は続いていきそうです。
Yes. It feels like summer is going to continue for a while.
あ、湊あくあさんのダンスが
Ah, Minato Aqua's dance
すごく可愛らしくて、目に入りましたね。
was so cute, it really caught my eye.
いやーいいですね。
Yeah, it was nice.
夏のお嬢さんと夏のお母さんでしたね。
They were like the summer lady and the summer mom.
そうですね。
That's right.
親子での共演でしたね。
A performance by mother and daughter.
アクアさんのお母さんはマリンさんですからね。
Because Aqua-san's mom is Marine-san.
そうですね。
That's right.
そして「渚のシンドバッド」。
And then "Nagisa no Sinbad."
こちらは、イナニスさんが初めてこの曲を歌うのに、とても練習してくださったそうで。
I heard Ina'nis-san practiced this song a lot since it was her first time singing it.
もー、すごくお上手でしたね。
She was really good at it.
はい。日本語でね、すごく上手に歌っていただきました。
Yes. She sang it very well in Japanese.
とっても可愛らしかったですね。
It was very cute.
はい。
Yes.
そして「RIDE ON TIME」。
And then "RIDE ON TIME."
こちらはぐらさんの大得意な、十八番の曲ですね。
This is a song Gura-san is very good at, it's her specialty.
いやー、そうですね。
Yes, it is.
はい、とっても歌枠とかでも聞いております。
Yes, I've heard it many times in her karaoke streams.
はい。
Yes.
というわけで、お次の曲なんですが。
So, onto the next song.
はい。
Yes.
その前に、なんと緊急情報で。
But before that, we have some urgent news.
緊急情報。
Urgent news.
はい。マリンさんの髪型が新しく...
Yes. Marine-san's hairstyle is newly...
お。
Oh.
新しく追加されるんですか？
Being added as a new one?
そのようです。
It seems so.
なんと！それはとっても楽しみですね。
Wow! I'm really looking forward to it.
ちょっと楽しみにしておきましょう。
Let's look forward to seeing it.
はい。
Yes.
そして、最後の曲となります。
And now, it's time for the final song.
もう最後ですか。
Is it already the last one?
そうなんです。
That's right.
あっという間ですね。お時間は。
Time flies, doesn't it?
寂しいですね。
It's a bit sad.
そうですね。
Yes.
はい。それでは最後の曲、参りましょう。
Alright. Let's move on to the final song.
「なんてったってアイドル」。
"Nantettatte Idol."
どうぞ！
Please enjoy!
なんてったってアイドル
Nantettatte Idol
赤いコンバーチブルから
From a red convertible
ドアをあけずに飛びおりて
I'll jump out without opening the door
ミニのスカートひらりで
With a flutter of my mini skirt
男の子達の視線を釘づけ
I'll fix the boys' gazes on me
黒いサングラスかけても
Even if I wear black sunglasses
プライバシーをかくしても
Even if I hide my privacy
ちょっとくらいは誰かに
At least for a little bit, someone
そうよ私だと気づかなくちゃイヤ・イヤ
Yes, has to realize it's me, or I'll hate it!
恋をするにはするけど
I do fall in love, but...
スキャンダルならノーサンキュー
No thank you to scandals
イメージが大切よ
My image is important
清く正しく美しく
Pure, righteous, and beautiful
なんてったってアイドル
After all, I'm an idol
私はアイドル
I am an idol
なんてったってアイドル
After all, I'm an idol
ステキなアイドル
A wonderful idol
アイドルはやめられない
I can't stop being an idol
Yeah!
なんてったってアイドル
After all, I'm an idol
Yeah!
ちょっといかしたタイプの
Even if I date a somewhat
ミュージシャンとつき合っても
cool type of musician
知らぬ存ぜぬととぼけて
I'll feign ignorance and
レポータ達をけむに巻いちゃうわ
throw the reporters off the scent
ずっとこのままでいたい
I want to stay like this forever
年なんかはとりたくない
I don't want to get older
いつもみんなにキャー・キャー
I want to keep hearing everyone
言われ続けたい 楽しければいい
screaming for me, as long as it's fun
恋をするにはするけど
I do fall in love, but...
インタビューならノーコメント
No comment for interviews
マネージャーをとおして
Go through my manager
清く正しく美しく
Pure, righteous, and beautiful
なんてったってアイドル
After all, I'm an idol
このままアイドル
Staying an idol
なんてったってアイドル
After all, I'm an idol
いつでもアイドル
Always an idol
アイドルはやめられない
I can't stop being an idol
Yeah!
Yeah! なんてったってアイドル
Yeah! After all, I'm an idol
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Hoo!
バイバーイ！
Bye bye!
宝鐘マリン、兎田ぺこら、
Houshou Marine, Usada Pekora,
不知火フレア、白銀ノエル、
Shiranui Flare, Shirogane Noel,
ホロライブ3期生で「なんてったってアイドル」でした！
It was Hololive Gen 3 with "Nantettatte Idol"!
いや、とってもアイドルしてましたね。プリプリでしたね。
Man, they were really being idols. They were so bouncy.
プリプリでしたね。
They really were.
可愛かったです。
They were cute.
白銀ノエルさんは2回出てましたね。
Shirogane Noel-san appeared twice, didn't she?
そうですね。
That's true.
あ、今回のキャスティングはちょっと、2回はミスったみたいです。
Ah, it seems there was a bit of a mistake in the casting...
あ、なんか本人がそう言ってましたね。
appearing twice. Ah, I think she said that herself.
そうですね。はい。
Right. Yes.
新しい髪型もよかったですね。
The new hairstyle was great too.
すごくね、あの、可愛らしかったですね。
It was really, um, very lovely.
そうですね。はい。
Yes. Indeed.
こちら、あの、実は案として、
Actually, as a proposal for this,
ポニーテールもよかったんですけども、
the ponytail was good, but...
あかさあい先生がラフの時点でモヒカンを提案していたそうで。
apparently Akasa Ai-sensei proposed a mohawk at the rough sketch stage.
モヒカンですか！？
A mohawk!?
そうでした。新髪型にモヒカンを...
That's right. A mohawk for the new hairstyle...
そんなの、あるわけないだろー！
There's no way that would happen!
さっきからでぇ、聞いてればぁ、
Listen here, you've been
わけのわからないごじょうほうを、たれながすのはやめてくださいよー。
spouting all sorts of nonsense, so please stop spreading misinformation!
本当だと思ってたんですけど。ちょっとそのキャラやめろもう。
I thought it was true. Stop with that character already.
ねぇ。そのキャラやめろ。
Yeah. Stop that character.
このキャラでやれって言ったやんけー！
You told me to do this character!
いや、まあ...やれって言った覚えはあります。覚えはあります。
Well... I do recall saying to do it. I do recall.
いいです。もういいです。
It's fine. It's fine now.
あ、いつも通りね、戻ってまいりました。はい。
Ah, she's back to normal now. Yes.
フブちゃんとミオ先輩、本当に今回MCありがとうございました。
Fubu-chan and Mio-senpai, thank you so much for the MC work.
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
いや、すごい絶妙なMCの空気感が...
Man, that exquisite MC atmosphere...
楽しかったー！
That was fun!
あの、圧ゴミ…言いたい、モヤモヤしちゃった。
That thick crowd... I wanted to say it, it felt hazy.
言いたかった、モヤモヤしちゃったね、なりました。
We wanted to say it, it did feel hazy, didn't it?
ところで、ところで、この髪型ちょっとどうかな？
By the way, by the way, how's this hairstyle?
おー！超かわいい！
Oh! So cute!
かわいいかな？どうかな？
Is it cute? What do you think?
サイドポニテやっぱいいね。
A side ponytail really is nice.
もう一つさ、もっと気づくことない？
One more thing, don't you notice anything else?
気づくこと？何だろう、何だろう？
Notice something? What could it be?
情報は髪型だけではなかった。
The hair wasn't the only update.
あ！イヤリングついてる！
Oh! You're wearing earrings!
気づいちゃった？
You noticed?
え、これ待って何柄なの？何柄だ？
Wait, what's the pattern? What pattern is it?
ちょっと見えてる？
Can you see it a bit?
あ、本当だ！あ、ハートのね！
Oh, it's true! Oh, it's a heart!
ハートだ！揺れている！かわいい！
It's a heart! It's swaying! Cute!
ね、これかわいい、え、めっちゃかわいい！
Right, this is cute. It's super cute!
え、待って待って、ほら後ろ！
Wait, wait, look at my back!
後ろも見て！後ろ姿！あ、いいね後ろ姿！
Look at the back too! My back! The back looks nice!
後ろ向いて！
Turn around!
あ、ちょっと見えなくなっちゃう…
Oh, I'm fading away...
それではですね、お時間がやってまいりました。
Well then, the time has come.
あっという間の時間でございました。
The time passed in the blink of an eye.
やばい、あっという間！終わる！
Oh no, so fast! It's ending!
宝鐘マリン3周年記念ホロライブ昭和歌謡祭、終了のお時間でございます。
Houshou Marine's 3rd Anniversary Hololive Showa Song Festival is now over.
ここまでご視聴くださった皆様、どうもありがとうございました！
Thank you all so much for watching until the end!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
また次回の歌謡祭でお会いいたしましょう！ありがとうございました！
Let's meet again at the next Song Festival! Thank you!
それでは、さようなら！
Well then, goodbye!
さようなら！
Goodbye!
え、ちょっと待って！行かないで！
Wait, wait a minute! Don't go!
まだ紹介したいものが…あの、昭和歌謡祭どうでした？
I still have things to introduce... Um, how was the Showa Song Festival?
ちょっとこの新しい趣、ちょっとバイバイじゃないから…
This new vibe, wait, it's not time for bye-bye yet...
まだ紹介があるんです、ちょっと、ちょっと！
I still have announcements to make, wait, wait!
終 制作・著作 マリン
End. Produced/Copyrighted by Marine
君たち！昭和歌謡祭どうでしたか？
You guys! How was the Showa Song Festival?
楽しんでいただけたでしょうか？
Did you all enjoy it?
さて、嬉しい告知とグッズ紹介をさせていただきますので、ぜひ最後まで聞いていってくださいね。
Now, I'll be making some happy announcements and introducing merchandise, so please listen until the end.
さあ、今年も出ますよ！宝鐘マリン活動3周年記念グッズです！
Now, they're coming out this year too! Houshou Marine 3rd Anniversary goods!
まずは、こちら。船長と宅飲みアクリルジオラマスタンドです！
First is this. The "Drinking at home with the Captain" acrylic diorama stand!
奥行きを感じるアクリルジオラマ。お母さんのあかさあい先生描き下ろしです。
An acrylic diorama that feels deep. It's newly drawn by my "mother" Akasa Ai-sensei.
君と宅飲みしているマリンというコンセプトなんですが…そしたらこのマリンと一緒に飲みたいですよね。
The concept is Marine drinking at home with you... so you'd want to drink with this Marine, wouldn't you?
そのためにこちら！船長描き下ろしコースターです！
For that purpose, we have this! A coaster newly drawn by the Captain!
めっちゃかわいいでしょ？どんなに可愛くても容赦なく上にグラスを乗せてください。
Isn't it super cute? No matter how cute it is, please put a glass on top without mercy.
いや、でもグラスがないよね。そのためにこちら！ドクロくん盃です！
Well, but you don't have a glass, do you? For that purpose, we have this! The Skull-kun sake cup!
ついに出たかって感じですよね。船長もお酒飲むときはこれ使うから、一緒にドクロくんで乾杯しようや。
Feels like it's finally here, doesn't it? I use this when I drink too, so let's toast together with Dokuro-kun!
飲み物を飲む用、崇める用、ペン立てる用…まあこれで3つは欲しいな。
For drinking, for worshipping, for holding pens... well, I want three of these.
そしてついでにこちらもどうですか？海賊船プレート！
And while we're at it, how about this? The pirate ship plate!
おつまみを乗せるいい感じの皿欲しいよな。
You want a nice plate to put snacks on, don't you?
まあ何かね、おつまみだけじゃなくアクセとか小物とか乗せてもいいし…まあこの船は何だって乗せるぜ。
Well, you can put snacks, accessories, or small items on it too... well, this ship will carry anything.
そして全てのセットをご購入いただきましたらば…数量限定直筆メッセージ入りポストカードと、船長と宅飲みラブラブ特典ボイスがついてきます。
And if you purchase the full set... you'll get a limited-quantity postcard with a handwritten message and a "lovey-dovey drinking at home with the Captain" bonus voice.
数量限定がなくなっても複製メッセージバージョンもあるので安心です。
Even if the limited quantities run out, there's a printed message version, so don't worry.
はい、今回はね、飲み会セットなコンセプトでした。22時から販売開始です。ぜひぜひゲットしてくださいね！
Yes, this time the concept was a drinking party set. Sales start at 22:00. Please get them!
そして超絶朗報です！船長描き下ろしのLINEスタンプ、このあと22時頃から販売開始です！
And I have amazing news! LINE stamps newly drawn by the Captain will start selling around 22:00!
いやマジでもう描くのが大変すぎたから…本当に君たち全員使ってくれないと普通に発狂しそう。
No, seriously, it was so hard to draw them... if you all don't use them, I'm literally going to go crazy.
いっぱい考えて徹夜で描き散らかしたから、絶対ゲットしてくださいね！
I thought about them so much and stayed up all night scribbling them out, so please definitely get them!
ということで、見てくれてありがとうございました！
With that, thank you so much for watching!
4年目も船長についてきてくださいね！それではいきますよ！出航！
Please keep following the Captain in her 4th year! Here we go! Set sail!